<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="mipa.intro">
  <title>What is MIPA?</title>

  <para>We first briefly introduce context-aware computing. Then we discuss why we need MIPA in building context-aware applications. </para>

  <para>1. Context-aware computing</para>
  <para>Pervasive applications are typically context-aware, using various kinds of contexts, such as location and time, to provide smart services. Context-aware applications need to monitor whether contexts bear specified property, thus being able to adapt to the pervasive computing environment accordingly. This brings the critical issue of context consistency checking, i.e. checking of specified constraints on properties of contexts.</para>

<para>Context consistency checking is especially challenging in asynchronous environments, where the computing entities do not have a global clock and communications suffer from finite but arbitrary delay. Moreover, context collecting devices (often resource-constrained sensors) may also delay the dissemination of context data due to resource constraints. The asynchrony caused by different data dissemination rates on different devices cannot be easily solved by existing clock synchronization schemes.</para>

<para>Predicate detection is a promising approach to context consistency checking in asynchronous environments. Predicate detection basically relies on the classical Lamport's definition of the happen-before relationship resulting from message causality, and its "on the fly" coding given by logical vector clocks.</para>
  
  <para>2. Achieving context-awareness based on MIPA in asynchronous pervasive computing environments</para>
  <para>We develop the Middleware Infrastructure for Predicate detection in Asynchronous environments (MIPA), to support Predicate Detection-based Consistency Checking for pervasive context (PDCC) in pervasive computing environments. MIPA aims at supporting the development and deployment of various predicate detection-based context consistency checking schemes for different pervasive computing scenarios.</para>
  
  <note>
	<para>MIPA is an open-source middleware currently hosted on Googlecode at http://mipa.googlecode.com/.</para>
	<para>Please refer to our techical papers [], to find further disucssions on the research issues in designing, implementing and using MIPA. </para>
  </note>

</chapter>