<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="mipa.intro">
  <title>What is MIPA?</title>

  <para>We first briefly introduce context-aware computing. Then we discuss why we need MIPA in building context-aware applications. </para>

  <sect1 id="mipa.intro.section-1">
    <title>Context-aware Computing</title>
    <para>Pervasive computing creates environments that embed computation and communication in a way that organically interacts with humans to enhance or ease their daily behavior. Contexts refer to the pieces of information that capture the characteristics of computing environments, and context-awareness allows applications to dynamically adapt to the pervasive computing environment.
</para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="mipa.intro.section-2">
      <title>PDPC - Property Detection for Pervasive Context</title>
    <para>PDPC (Property Detection for Pervasive Context) is one of the primary approaches to achieving context-awareness. Specifically, context-aware applications need to detect whether contexts bear user-specified properties, in order to adapt their behavior accordingly. For example, in a smart office scenario, the user may specify a constraint on property of the contexts: "Location of the user is the lecture room and a presentation is going on in the lecture room". Thus the application can adaptively turn mobile phone of the user to vibration mode when the property is satisfied. Moreover, contexts are often error-prone due to noises. Users may specify properties which accurate contexts must obey, in order to prune noisy contexts. For example, users may specify that: "no one appears in two different places at the same time", to make sure that the location context is correctly collected.</para>
</sect1>

  <sect1 id="mipa.intro.section-3">
      <title>Achieving Context-awareness Based on MIPA in Asynchronous Pervasive Computing Environments</title>

      <para> We develop MIPA - the Middleware Infrastructure for Predicate detection in Asynchronous environments - to support PDPC in pervasive computing environments. MIPA aims at supporting the development and deployment of various predicate detection-based context consistency checking schemes for different pervasive computing scenarios. </para>

    <note>
      <para>MIPA is an open-source middleware currently hosted on Googlecode at http://mipa.googlecode.com/.</para>
      <para>Please refer to our techical papers
	<footnote>
	  <para> Yu Huang, Xiaoxing Ma, Jiannong Cao, Xianping Tao and Jian Lu, Concurrent Event Detection for Asynchronous Consistency Checking of Pervasive Context, in proc. of the 7th Annual IEEE Intl. Conf. on Pervasive Computing and Communications (PerCom), 2009. </para>
	</footnote>
	<footnote>
	  <para> Yu Huang, Jianping Yu, Jiannong Cao, Xiaoxing Ma, Xianping Tao, Jian Lu, Checking Behavioral Consistency Constraints for Pervasive Context in Asynchronous Environments, Technical report TR090709-MOPEC-ICS-NJU, Institute of Computer Software, Nanjing University, Sep. 2009. </para>
	</footnote>
	<footnote>
	<para> Jianping Yu, Yu Huang, Jiannong Cao, Xiaoxing Ma, Xianping Tao, Jian Lu, Middleware Infrastructure for Predicate Detection-based Consistency Checking of Pervasive Context, Technical report TR101409-MOPEC-ICS-NJU, Institute of Computer Software, Nanjing University, Nov. 2009. </para>
	</footnote>
	, to find further disucssions on the research issues in designing, implementing and using MIPA. </para>
    </note>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
